# Rupin Solanki

Delhi. India

rupinism123@gmail.com

linkedin.com/in/rupin-solanki-437648203

## Summary

DevOps Engineer with a primary focus on build, release, secure, monitor, and software configuration management.

Skilled in Research, Penetration Testing, Web Application Security, Training, and Ethical Hacking. Strong engineering professional with a Bachelor of Science - BS focused in Computer Science from Shaheed Sukhdev College Of Business Studies.

## **Experience**



#### DevOps Engineer-1

**Dangal Games** 

Sep 2021 - Present (8 months +)

Experienced in hosting applications using cloud-based services like AWS EC2, VPC, RDS, CloudWatch, S3, Cloudfront, AWS Kubernetes, etc

- Experience in deploying microservices on Kubernetes without zero downtime
- Experience working with various flavors of Linux with key focuses on scripting and automation
- Experience designing and building web and mobile application environments on AWS using EKS.
- EC2, VPC, RDS, and other services
- Configure AWS WAF to secure Applications.
- Responsible for CI/CD release management using JENKINS and GITHUB.
- Establish continuous integration (CI JENKINS-tool) pipeline to fully automate build deployment.
- Bash scripting to automate containerized application deployment, designing, managing, and maintaining tools to automate operational processes.
- Experience in working within a concentrated infrastructure domain compute, networking, storage, infrastructure security
- Configured Monitoring tools like Cadvisor, Prometheus, and NewRelic for Docker and Kubernetes Clusters.

#### Web App Penetration Testing Intern

PlatinumGate Technologies Pvt Ltd

Jan 2021 - Feb 2021 (2 months)

- Perform security tests on networks, web-based applications, and computer systems.
- Built and secure the web-based application and computer systems



#### Vulnerability Assessment and Penetration Testing Intern

Cryptus Cyber Security Private Limited

Oct 2020 - Dec 2020 (3 months)

Research, recommend, evaluate and implement information security solutions that identify and protect against potential threats, and respond to security violations, misuse of resources or noncompliance situations using defined escalation processes.

### **Education**



## Shaheed Sukhdev College Of Business Studies

Bachelor of Science - BS, Computer Science 2018 - 2021

#### **Skills**

Amazon Web Services (AWS) • DevOps • Kubernetes • Docker • Linux • Web Application Security • Continuous Integration and Continuous Delivery (CI/CD) • Nginx • Infrastructure as code (IaC) • Ansible